DAVID OWOPETU

308 Georgian Drive Barrie, Ontario L4M 0K5 <u>olanrewajudavid@gmail.com</u> +1 249 989 5255

WEB DEVELOPER - DATA ENGINEER

A versatile Tech Professional with 10 years' experience in providing IT services for clients in data acquisition, data engineering, software applications and development support operations. Saddled with strong organizational skills and ability to effectively prioritize workflows and multitask. Recently undergoing a Post Graduate Course in Big Data Analytics at Georgian College, Canada, to further explore the world of big data and apply same to industry best practices.

Areas of Expertise:

- Front End Developer
- Word Press Developer
- DevOps

- Full Stack Web Developer
- Data Acquisition
- Linux / Shell Scripting

- PHP Developer
- Agile Methodology
- Analytical Thinking

"David Owopetu came in at the right time when NIMASA needed a professional to customize a form to be used by the agency for proper documentations of cargo ships. David was very assiduous and developed the application in a very shortest possible period. He is vast and a reliable tech enthusiast" - Engr Femi Adegbola (NIMASA, NG)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Software Programming: PHP, SQL, NodeJS, Python, Linux, APIs, Ajax, jQuery, JavaScript, Reacts, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap

DevOps: Linux Server Administration, Shell scripting, Dockers, AWS Cloud, Jenkins, CI/CD, Dockers, Kubernetes

Platforms: Apache Server, Nginx Server, Linux Server, Git Bash, GitHub, VSCode, Maria DB, MySQL Server, Laravel, Magento, WordPress, Power BI, Tableau, Slack, Office 365, AWS Server.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Big Data Analytics, (Post Graduate Certificate)

Georgian College, Barrie, ON

Physics (Bachelor's Degree)

Obafemi Awolowo University, Osun state, Nigeria Jan 2024 – Aug 2024

Sep 2001 – Aug 2009

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Application Developer

Laurel Analytiq Ltd, Lagos, Nigeria

Jan 2018 - Present

- Designs an integrated database for clients using MongoDB that leverage React architecture to yield on demand and detailed feedback
- Develops UI with modern JavaScript framework, Reacts, HTML5 and CSS3 which improved user satisfaction by 27%
- Works on both front-end and back-end aspects of web applications to ensure end-to-end functionality
- Managed front end architecture and implemented PHP code on WooCommerce plug-ins of zeeliciousfoods.com that improved user experience and increased revenue by 45%.
- Collaborates with cross-functional teams, including designers, product managers, and QA engineers, to deliver integrated solutions
- Troubleshoots and implements web applications on Apache web server to ensure 99.99% uptime
- Ensuring data consistency across all client's Database at zero tolerance for data breech till date

Data Acquisition Engineer

Sep 2018 – Oct 2023

Visuna, UK (Consulting for Expro World Wide, Saudi)

- Developed application templates using Excel and SQL that enhanced company's easy access and manipulation of acquired field data
- Represented data in visual graphs and dashboards using Excel that enhanced stake holder's useful decision
- Engaged in Data Acquisition, data cleaning, quality assessment, data interpretation and analysis to improve company's data compliances
- Created a model for reporting channels to clients and stakeholders that improved company's quality performance delivery by 35%
- Managed company's DBMS on AWS Cloud infrastructure while optimizing and ensuring data consistency.

Web Programmer / Trainer

Apr 2013 – Aug 2018

Vast Integrated Solutions, PH, Nigeria

- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
 AJAX and JSON coding
- Created a customized email campaign templates that enhanced effective marketing and save company cost of purchasing marketing tools
- Wrote clean reusable PHP/MYSQL codes for backend applications, enhancing optimal application deliverability to clients.
- Trained Junior designers on web development with 98% customer feedback satisfaction
- Created an offline web application form for NIMASA, using JQuery/PHP/MySQL that increased the client's efficiency and effective file management
- Managed web hosting server ensuring 99.99% uptime while leveraging on cron job technologies

CERTIFICATIONS	
Certificate in DevOps / AWS Cloud Architect	Jan 2023 – Present
Certificate in Python for Data Science, AI and Development (IBM)	May 2023
Certificate in Data Foundation (Google)	Apr 2023
Certificate in Data Analytics (Udemy)	Mar 2023
MEAN STACK (Simplilearn)	Feb 2021
Certificate in Advanced Web Development	Jul 2013
VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE	
Web/Database Administrator	Nov 2013 – Present

Nigerian Community in Barrie, Canada

 Initiated and introduced a concept of creating database and website for Nigerian Community in Barrie for easy and access and communication amongst members

Assists in organizing voluntary donation programs to at least one hundred (100) of beneficiary members